http://www.antar.org.au/privacy-policy

Jump to Navigation
You are here: Home / Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy sets out how ANTaR uses your personal information and explains:What kind of personal information ANTaR collects and how it is collectedHow ANTaR uses the information you provideDisclosureMerchandiseHow ANTaR treats sensitive informationManagement and security of personal informationUpdating personal informationSeeking access to the personal information ANTaR holds about youHow to contact ANTaRANTaR Inc owns and operates the website www.antar.org.au.This policy applies to the collection of all personal information by ANTaR whether on the ANTaR website or through written or printed matter such as petitions or order forms.ANTaR is bound by the National Privacy Principles contained in the Commonwealth Privacy Act. ANTaR may, from time to time, review and update this privacy policy to take account of new laws and technology and changes to ANTaR's operations. All personal information held by ANTaR will be governed by its most recent policy, posted on ANTaR’s website.What kind of personal information ANTaR collects and how it is collectedANTaR collects personal information from a variety of sources, including from members of the public, prospective employees, prospective and current volunteers, contractors and partner organisations.In general, the personal information ANTaR collects includes (but is not limited to) name, address, contact details, date of birth, gender, occupation, in some cases membership of professional associations, special requirements, expressed interests and, where relevant, financial information, including credit card information and banking details.Personal information you provide: The personal information you enter on ANTaR’s website or give to ANTaR in other ways is stored by ANTaR. We obtain most personal information through ANTaR supporter and fundraising activities and ANTaR’s donation appeals. You may provide information when you make a donation to ANTaR, purchase merchandise from ANTaR, sign a statement of support for an ANTaR campaign, request or acquire a product or service from ANTaR, complete a survey or questionnaire, enter a competition, participate in forums or when you communicate with ANTaR by e-mail, telephone or in writing (for example if you contact ANTaR’s office or provide feedback).Indirect collection: ANTaR endeavours to collect personal information about an individual only from that individual. In some circumstances ANTaR may obtain personal information from a third party. If you provide personal information about another person to ANTaR, ANTaR requires that you inform that person you have done so and provide them with a copy of this policy.How ANTaR uses the information you provideANTaR may use information it collects from you for the primary purpose for which it is collected and for such other secondary purposes that are related to the primary purpose of collection. ANTaR generally uses personal information to:provide you with products or services you have requested;communicate with you by mail, e-mail or telephone;provide you with ongoing information about opportunities in which ANTaR believes you may be interested; andhelp ANTaR manage and enhance its activities.In some cases where ANTaR asks you to provide information about yourself, if you do not provide ANTaR with that information, ANTaR may not be able to provide you with the requested product or service.DisclosureANTaR may disclose personal information to ANTaR’s state and territory affiliates. Your personal information, if disclosed to ANTaR affiliates, will only be used as set out in this privacy policy.ANTaR may also provide your information to third parties engaged by ANTaR to perform functions on its behalf, such as processing credit card information, mailouts, marketing and research. Such third parties must comply with this privacy policy or a similar privacy policy and not disclose your personal information or use it for any purpose other than that specified by ANTaR.MerchandiseYou may wish to purchase merchandise from the ANTaR website by placing orders via the online shop, merchandise form or by placing a telephone order. In order to complete the order, you must supply ANTaR with personal information, including your name, phone number, address, e-mail address, credit card details, postcode and country of residence. ANTaR will treat your personal information in accordance with this privacy policy.How ANTaR treats sensitive information"Sensitive Information" means information relating to a person's racial or ethnic origin, membership of political bodies, religion, membership of a trade union or professional or trade association, sexual preferences, criminal record and health. ANTaR may use and disclose Sensitive Information only for the purpose for which it was provided or a directly related secondary purpose or as allowed by law unless you have agreed otherwise.Management and security of personal informationANTaR's National Director oversees the management of personal information in accordance with this privacy policy and the Commonwealth Privacy Act.ANTaR protects the personal information ANTaR holds from misuse, loss, unauthorised access, modification or disclosure by various means including firewalls, password access, secure servers and encryption of credit card transactions.Updating personal informationANTaR endeavours to ensure that the personal information it holds is accurate, complete and up-to-date. You can update your information by contacting us.Where personal information is no longer required by ANTaR, it will be destroyed or de-identified.Seeking access to the personal information ANTaR holds about youYou have the right to seek access the personal information held about you and to advise ANTaR of any inaccuracy. There are some exceptions to this right set out in the Privacy Act.If you make an access request, ANTaR will ask you to verify your identity and specify what information you require.How to contact ANTaRIf you have enquiries or wish to provide feedback about this policy, please contact us here.
Current Campaigns
Time for Treaty
Read our resource ‘Treaty in Australia’ which examines what Treaty is, the history of Treaties with First Nations here and elsewhere, and where we are now. Take action and support the movement for Treaties in Australia.
Read more…
Submissions and Reports
Critical to our advocacy is supporting the voice of First Nations people and their rights in submissions to the public inquiries of governments, parliaments, royal commissions and other public commissions.
Read more…
Help ANTaR to continue to campaign for the rights of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander peoples by making a donation.
Agileware | Developing and supporting Drupal websites since 2002
Newism | Helping brands and agencies build successful businesses online
